ROBINSON MWAURA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+254790772286

robinsonmwaura254@gmail.com

Nairobi, Kenya

PROFILE

I am a software developer having expertise in frontend development and exposure to back- end development. I design and develop web applications using the latest technologies to deliver the product with quality code. Strong creative and analytical skills. Team player with an eye for detail.

EXPERIENCE

Portable Car Engineering Environment(PCEE) FRONT-END DEVELOPER

APR 2023-DEC 2023

- Translated designs and wire frames into high quality code and writing application interface with ReactJs.
- Troubleshot interface and debugged applications codes to improve functionality and performance by 50%.
- Tested and optimized react components for best performance across every device and browser.

HNG INTERNSHIP PROGRAM FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Nov 2022 - Jan 2023

- I used my extensive experience with front end development to define the structure and components for the project, making sure they are reusable.
- Keep the code quality high reviewing code from other developers and suggesting improvements.
- Interact with the designer to suggest changes and to make sure the view he has about the design is translated into actual functionality.

SKILLS

- Web Design
- JavaScript
- ReactJs
- Go
- Tailwind CSS
- HTML CSS
- MySQL
- Redux
- · Problem-Solving

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Dedan Kimathi University of Technology

2019- APR 2024

EDUCATION 2015-2018

Kenya secondary education Kihara secondary school

• B(plain)

REFERENCES

Clement Lipesa CEO PCEE +254 783 240838 clementlipe@yahoo.com

Michael Kagiri Lecturer(Dedan Kimathi University) +254715998222

Cliff Manyara
Colleague
+254791613485
cliffmanyara254@gmail.com